Finding Aid for Treasurer (University of Michigan) records, 1839-1920
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Treasurer (University of Michigan) records
1839-1920
University of Michigan. Treasurer.
87333 BImu Bimu B8 2
Treasurer's records include letterbooks, disbursements, receipts, ledgers, journals, balance books, daybooks, payroll books, and other business records.
2 linear feet
85 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Circumstances of the acquisition of the records are unknown.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
The office of University Treasurer was established in 1817 under the auspices of the "The University of Michigania" but it is unclear when the first treasurer, James Abbott, actually assumed his position. The office was continued through various reorganizations of the Board of Regents and was the university's principal financial officer through 1931 when president Ruthven undertook a major restructuring of the university's administrative offices.
Treasurers of the University of Michigan
1820 James Abbott
1821 Abraham Edwards
1821-1823 James Abbott
1823-1837 G. Mott Williams
1837-1839 John Norton
1839-1841 Henry K. Sanfger
1941-1844 Alexander H. Sibley
1944-1846 John Johnstone Adam
1846-1848 Digby V. Bell
1948-1851 John Johnstone Adam
1851-1858 John Manley Chase
1858-1860 Henry Webster Welles
1860-1864 Volney Chapin
1864-1872 Donald McIntyre
1872-1878 John Marshall Wheeler
1878-1883 William Addison Tolchard
1883-1908 Harrison Soule
1908-1911 George Sumner Baker
1911-1931 Robert Alexander Campbell
Treasurer's records include letterbooks, disbursements, receipts, ledgers, journals, balance books, daybooks, payroll books, and other business records. The records provide and insight into, though not a complete record of, the day-to-day financial operation of the university
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Administration.Administration.; University of Michigan--Finance.Finance.; University of Michigan--Gifts and loans.Gifts and loans.; University of Michigan--Students--Scholarships, fellowships, etc.StudentsScholarships, fellowships, etc.; University of Michigan. Treasurer.
- Records
  - Miscellaneous Records
    - Treasurers Reports, 1870-1882; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Letterbook of University Treasurer (Harrison Soule)
      - 1894-1898 (Box 1)
      - 1901-1905 (Box 1)
      - 1905-1909 (Box 1)
    - Janitor's records, 1852-1855 (Box 1)
    - Steward's Accounts, 1868-1869 (Box 1)
    - Draft book, October 1909-July 1911 (Box 1)
    - Ledger, 1884-1885 (Box 1)
    - Balance book, March 1908-May 1911 (Box 2)
    - Record Book re scholarships, fellowships and loan funds, 1897-1920 (Box 2)
    - Disbursements, June 1905-June 1910; 6 microfilms (Box 2)
    - Correspondence
      - 1891 (Box 2)
      - 1897-1901, 5 folders (Box 2)
      - 1909-1910, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Disbursements, 1852-1858; 1879-1905; 21 volumes
    - 1852-1858 (Volume 1)
    - July 3, 1876-February 11, 1879 (Volume 2)
    - February 1879-December 1882 (Volume 3)
    - Vol. [A], December 1882-March 1885 (Volume 4)
    - Vol. B, April 1885-April 1887 (Volume 5)
    - Vol. C, April 1887-May 1889 (Volume 6)
    - Vol. D, May 1889-December 1890 (Volume 7)
    - Vol. E, December 1890-April 1892 (Volume 8)
    - Vol. G,., October 1893-June 1894 (Volume 9)
    - Vol. H, July 1894-June 1895 (Volume 10)
    - Vol. I, July 1895-June 1896 (Volume 11)
    - Vol. J, July 1895-June 1897 (Volume 12)
    - Vol. K, July 1897-June 1898 (Volume 13)
    - Vol. L, July 1898-September 1899 (Volume 14)
    - Vol. M, October 1899-September 1900 (Volume 15)
    - Vol. N, October 1890-June 1901 (Volume 16)
    - Vol. O, July 1901-June 1902 (Volume 17)
    - Vol. P, July 1902-June 1903 (Volume 18)
    - Vol. Q, July 1903-June 1904 (Volume 19)
    - Vol. R, July 1904-June 1905 (Volume 20)
    - Vol. S, June 1905-June 1910 (Volume 21)
    - Vol. S, June 1905-June 1910; 6 microfilms (Box 2)
  - Receipts,1839-1854, 1883-1905; 21 volumes
    - May 1839-May 1854 (Box 1)
    - Vol. A, October 1883-September 1884 (Volume 22)
    - Vol. B, October 1884-December 1885 (Volume 23)
    - Vol. C, December 1885-December 1887 (Volume 24)
    - Vol. D, October 1807-June 1889 (Volume 25)
    - Vol. E, June 1889-April 1890 (Volume 26)
    - Vol. F, April 1890-March 1891 (Volume 27)
    - Vol. G, March 1891-June 1892 (Volume 28)
    - Vol. H, July 1892-September 1893 (Volume 29)
    - Vol. I, October 1893-June 1894 (Volume 30)
    - Vol. J, July 1894-June 1895 (Volume 31)
    - Vol. K, July 1895-June 1896 (Volume 32)
    - Vol. L, July 1896-June 1897 (Volume 33)
    - Vol. M, July 1897-June 1898 (Volume 34)
    - Vol. N, July 1898-June 1899 (Volume 35)
    - Vol. O, July 1899-June 1900 (Volume 36)
    - Vol. P, July 1900-June 1901 (Volume 37)
    - Vol. Q, July 1901-June 1902 (Volume 38)
    - Vol. R, July 1902-June 1903 (Volume 39)
    - Vol. S, July 1903-June 1904 (Volume 40)
    - Vol. T, July 1904-June 1905 (Volume 41)
  - Ledgers, 1854; 1869-1875; 1878-1910; 11 volumes
    - Vol. 2, 1890-1894 (Volume 42)
    - Vol. 3, 1894-1898 (Volume 43)
    - Vol. 4, 1898-1902 (Volume 44)
    - Vol. 5, 1902-1905 (Volume 45)
    - Vol. 6, 1905-1908 (Volume 46)
    - Vol. 7, 1908 (Volume 47)
    - Vol. A, 1878-1910 (Volume 48)
    - 1854 (Volume 49)
    - 1869-1875 (Volume 50)
    - 1883-1890 (Volume 51)
    - 1884-1885 (Box 1)
  - Journals, 1878-1910; 16 volumes
    - Vol. A, July 1878-October 1881 (Volume 52)
    - Vol. B, October 1881-September 1884 (Volume 53)
    - Vol. B, October 1884-December 1890 (Volume 54)
    - Vol. C, December 1890-June 1895 (Volume 55)
    - Vol. D, July 1895-April 1899 (Volume 56)
    - Vol. E, May 1899-September 1902 (Volume 57)
    - Vol. F, October 1902-August 1905 (Volume 58)
    - Vol. G, September 1905-June 1908 (Volume 59)
    - Vol. H, June 1908-June 1910 (Volume 60)
    - Vol. I, October 1884-July 1893 (Volume 61)
    - Vol. B, July 1893-December 1894 (Volume 62)
    - Vol. C, 1894-October 1900 (Volume 63)
    - Vol. D, October 1900-April 1905 (Volume 64)
    - Vol. E, April 1905-November 1908 (Volume 65)
    - Vol. F, December 1908-1910 (Volume 66)
    - November 1904-April 1907 (Volume 67)
  - Balance Books, 1876-1911; 6 volumes
    - 1876-1878 (Volume 68)
    - 1882-1890 (Volume 69)
    - 1901-1912 (Volume 70)
    - 1905-1909 (Volume 71)
    - 1909-1912 (Volume 72)
    - 1908-1911 (Box 2)
  - Pay Roll Books, 1899-1910; 5 volumes
    - March 1899-December 1900 (Volume 73)
    - January 1901-June 1903 (Volume 74)
    - July 1903-June 1905 (Volume 75)
    - July 1905-April 1908 (Volume 76)
    - May 1908-June 1910 (Volume 77)
  - Inventories of University Property, 1861; 1864; 1889-1911; 2 volumes
    - 1861, 1864 (Volume 78)
    - 1889-1911 (Volume 79)
      (largely property valuations)
  - Daybooks, 1837-1879; 4 volumes
    - 1837-1851 (Volume 80)
    - 1853-1854 (Volume 81)
    - 1869-1876 (Volume 82)
    - 1878-1879 (Volume 83)
  - Estimates
    - 1883, 1887-1888; 1 volumes (Volume 84)
      (cost estimates for various laboratory and facility construction and furnishing)
  - Vouchers
    - 1878-1879, 1 volumes (Volume 85)